Guide to the Big Red Band miscellany, 1905-2003.
Big Red Band miscellany, 1905-2003
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Big Red Band miscellany, 1905-2003.
37-6-3112
Cornell University.Big Red Marching Band.
7.5 cubic ft.
Audio Recordings, Computer Media, Correspondence, Memorabilia, Newspapers, Photographs, Publications, Scrapbooks
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Material documenting the history of the Cornell University Big Red Marching Band, including print and audio visual items.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
"Big Red Band Notes," newsletter; "Through the Years with the Big Red Band," 1990; clippings; t-shirts, 1983, 2001-2003; and alumni visor hat. Also, movie films of band shows from the late 1940s through the late 1950s. 16mm motion picture films of the Cornell Big Red Band in color and black and white. Includes footage of the bannd at Niagara, Princeton, Columbia 1948; University of Pennsylvania, n.d.; Presidential Review, 20 May, 1954; Coumbia 1 November 1958; Penn. crew formation. Other reels are unidentified.
Includes files, photographs, scrapbooks, and recordings.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University--Songs and music.; Cornell University--Societies,etc.
Subjects:
Cornell University--Students.; Music--Societies,etc.; Band music.; Marching bands.
Form and Genre Terms:
T-shirts.; Motion pictures (visual works).; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
See also Cornell University football motion pictures movies, videos, and film, #40-2-2205
SERIES LIST
Series I. Photo Albums and Scrapbooks
Boxes 1-2
Box 3 Folders 1-13
Box 8, 2 Albums
Box 9, 10
Series II. Photographs not in Albums
Box 3 Folders 14, 16-20, 22-83
Box 4 Folders 1-18, 30
Series III. Miscellaneous
Box 3 Folder 15, 21
Box 4 Folders 19-29, 31-36
Box 6, Bow, Buttons, 4 Plaques
Series IV. Media
Box 5, 5 tapes, 16 CDs
Box 6, 3 VHS, 1 BETA
Box 7, Reel to Reel Film, 5 Mini-Records, 17 Records, Box 12, 12 reels.
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Photo Albums and Scrapbooks
  - Cornell Band (Part I of II), 1905-1952 (Box 10, Folder Album 1)
  - Cornell Band (Part II of II), 1949-1952 (Box 10, Folder Album 2)
  - Cornell Band, 1952-1953 (Box 10, Folder Album 3)
  - Cornell Band, 1955-1957 (Box 10, Folder Album 4)
  - Cornell Band, 1957-1962 (Box 10, Folder Album 5)
  - Cornell Band, 1982-1984 (Box 10, Folder Album 6)
  - Photographs-1981 Scrapbook (Box 11, Folder 1-9)
  - Photographs-1981 Scrapbook (Box 11, Folder 10-14)
  - Photographs-1985 Scrapbook (Box 11, Folder 15-24)
  - Photographs-1986 Scrapbook (Box 11, Folder 25-32)
  - Presenting the 1987 Big Red Band and Alumni Band (Box 11, Folder 33-46)
  - Cornell Big Red Marching Band: The Only REAL Marching Band in the Ivy League, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 47-61)
  - The Only REAL Yearbook of the Only REAL Marching Band in the Ivy League Part I, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 62-74)
  - The Only REAL Yearbook of the Only REAL Marching Band in the Ivy League Part II, 1992-1993 (Box 11, Folder 75-91)
  - Big Red Band 1994 Scrapbook (Box 11, Folder 92-106)
  - The 2000 Cornell University Big Red Marching Band: Volume I (Box 11, Folder 107-108)
  - 2000 Scrapbook (Box 11, Folder 109-110)
  - The 2000 Cornell University Big Red Marching Band: Volume II (Box 3, Folder 1-12)
  - The 2000 Cornell University Big Red Marching Band: Volume III (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - The Only REAL Yearbook of the Only REAL Marching Band in the Ivy Leauge, 1995 (Box 8, Folder Album 1)
  - Photographs-1997-98 Scrapbook, 1997-1998 (Box 8, Folder Album 2)
- Series II. Photographs not in Albums
  - Photographs, 1921-1925 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Photographs, 1936-1946 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Negatives, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Photographs, 1947-1948 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Gerald Gordon Photographs, 1951-1954 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Photographs, 1953-1958 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Slides, 1957 (Box 3)
  - Photographs, 1961-1966 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Photographs, 1972-1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Photographs, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 24-28)
  - Snapshot Photographs, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Unlabled Photographs, c. 1976-1980 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Unlabled Negatives, c. 1976-1980 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Colgate/Cornell, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Big Red Band Storms Lake Placid, 1981 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Misc., 1981 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Photographs, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Photographs, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Slides, October 1984 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Photographs, 1984 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Photographs, 1986-1990 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Photographs, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Photographs, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Big Red Band Photographs, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 42-49)
  - Photographs, 1989-1990 (Box 3, Folder 50)
  - Slides, December 1990 (Box 3, Folder 51)
  - Photographs, Early 1990s (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - Photographs, September 1992 (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - Photographs, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - Photographs, 1993 (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - Big Red Band, 1994-1995 (Box 3, Folder 56-57)
  - Photographs, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 58)
  - Photographs, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 59)
  - Photographs, c.1996 (Box 3, Folder 60-67)
  - Photographs, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 68-82)
  - Photographs, 1996 (Box 3, Folder 83)
  - Big Red Band Photographs, c.1996 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Big Red Band Photographs, c. 1996 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Photographs, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Photographs-Cornell Pep Band, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Photographs, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Photographs, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Big Red Band Panorama Copies (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Section Photographs (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Trombones (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Big Red Band Photographs (Box 4, Folder 12-14)
  - Big Red Band Photographs (Box 4, Folder 15-18)
  - Big Red Band Large Print Group Photograph (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Big Red Band Negatives, 1959-1960 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Big Red Band Photographs (Box 4, Folder 21-25)
  - Oversize band photos see CD-1671 in Box 5 for a CD with scanned images of these photos, 1914-1970s (Box 9)
  - CD of scanned images of the oversize photographs found in box 9, 1914-1970s; CD-1671 (Box 5)
- Series III. Miscellaneous
  - New York Central Train Dinner Menu, October 9, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Publicity, 1960s-1980s (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Harry Chapin Letter (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Big Red Band Notes, 1989-2004 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Final Exams, 1982-1999 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Final Exams, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Band Finals (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, Constitutions, Publications, Programs, Scripts, Schedules, Rosters, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - History and Organization of Band Committee, 1947-1948 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Meeting Minutes, Correspondence, Rosters, Schedules, By-Laws, 1990s (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Articles and Clippings, 1938-1988 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Half Time Shows, 1975-1983 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Meeting Minutes, Constitutions, Certificates, etc., 1977-1998 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Big Red Band Notes, 1981-2001 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Big Red Band Notes, 2009, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Phone Lists and Rosters, 1984-2000 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Brochures, Schedules, Fliers, Programs, 1938-2006 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Sheet Music and Marching Diagrams, 1983, 1937-1938 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, 1982-1992 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Correspondence, 1969-1981 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Band Seniors Bow, 1986 (Box 6)
  - The Big Red Roof Inn Buttons Given to the Band in, 2005 (Box 6)
  - Plaque: Bandsmen of the Year, 1956-1972 (Box 6)
  - Plaque: Freshman Bandsmen of the Year, 1956-1972 (Box 6)
  - Plaque: Cornell Big Red Band Freshman of the Year, 1985-1997 (Box 6)
  - Plaque: Cornell Big Red Band Seniors of the Year, 1985-1997 (Box 6)
  - Big Red Band Notes, 1990-1998 (Box 1)
  - Misc. Correspondence, 1990s (Box 1)
  - Fall 1983 final exam (Box 1)
  - Five shirts and a hat, 1983-1984 (Box 2)
    Includes "I Played at Carnegie Hall" shirts. Cornell Museum items ids 1243, 1244, 1185-1188
- Series IV. Media
  - Record: Cornell University Concert Band, Cornell Radio Guild Inc., William A. Campbell, conductor., 1951; SR-1202 (Box 7)
  - Record: Cornell University Concert Band, 1959; SR-1203 (Box 7)
  - Record: Cornell University Concert Band, Bailey Hall, March 13, 1960; SR-1204 (Box 7)
  - Record: Cornell University Wind Ensemble, Marice Stith, conductor, Bailey Hall, March 9, 1969; SR-1205 (Box 7)
  - Record: Cornell University Wind Ensemble, Marice Stith, conductor, Bailey Hall, June 8, 1969; SR-1206 (Box 7)
  - Record: Cornell University Symphonic Band, Memorial Room, Willard Straight Hall, November 15, 1971; SR-1207 (Box 7)
  - Record: Cornell University Wind Ensemble, Bailey Hall, March 6, 1977; SR-1208 (Box 7)
  - Record: Cornell University Big Red Marching Band, Bailey Hall, November 15, 1977; SR-1209 (Box 7)
  - Record: Cornell University Big Red Marching Band Presents: Fight Songs of the North East, 1977; SR-1210 (Box 7)
    Features the band playing fight songs from Cornell, Army, boston college, Boston University, Brown, Bucknell, Columbia, Colgate, Dartmouth, Harvard, Holy Cross, Navy, Penn State, Pennsylvania University, Princeton, Pittsburgh, Rutgers, Syracuse, Temple, Vermont, Villanova, West Virginia and Yale.
  - Record: Cornell University Big Red Marching Band (2 copies), 1981; SR-1211, 1212 (Box 7)
  - Record: Cornell University Big Red Marching Band (2 copies), 1984; SR-1213, 1214 (Box 7)
  - Record: Cornell University Big Red Marching Band (2 copies), 1985; SR-1215, 1216 (Box 7)
  - 45s: The Big Red Band is on the loose (5 copies), 1986; SR-1217-1221 (Box 7)
  - Record: Cornell University Big Red Marching Band (2 copies), 1988; SR-1222, 1223 (Box 7)
  - Cornell Big Red Football Band, 1954; SR-31434 (Box 7)
  - Cornell Symphonic Band, 1948-1959; SR-31435 (Box 7)
  - Cornell University Symphonic Band - performance in Bailey Hall, 1962-01-07; SR-31436 (Box 7)
  - Cornell Music - Cornell Glee Club, Chimes, Concert Band, 1950; SR-31437 (Box 7)
    Cornell Alumni Association
  - Cornell University Concert Band, 1959; SR-31438 (Box 7)
  - Cornell 1955 Concert Band, SR-31439-31440 (Box 7)
  - Tape: Cornell University Big Red Marching Band, empty case, 1992; TR-9312 (Box 5)
  - Tape: Cornell University Big Red Marching Band (2 copies), 1995; TR-9313, 9314 (Box 5)
  - Tape: Cornell University Big Red Marching Band (2 copies), 1996; TR-9315, 9316 (Box 5)
  - Tape: Cornell University Symphonic Band, Bailey Hall, May 5, 1996; TR-9317 (Box 5)
  - CD: Through the years with the Cornell University Big Red Marching Band" (2 copies), 1996; CD-1655, 1656 (Box 5)
    Features recordings of the band from 1967 to 1996
  - CD: Cornell University Big Red Marching Band (2 copies), 1997; CD-1657, 1670 (Box 5)
  - CD: Live at Lynah, recording made during hockey games at Lynah Rink, also includes radio play by play., November 7-8, 1997; CD-1658 (Box 5)
  - CD: Cornell University Big Red Marching Band, 1999; CD-1659 (Box 5)
  - CD: Big Red Marching Band, 2000; CD-1660 (Box 5)
  - CD: Big Red Marching Band, 2001; CD-1661 (Box 5)
  - CD: Voices of the Faithful, recording made during hockey games at Lynah Rink, cover features the hockey team holding band instruments., February 1-2, 2002; CD-1662 (Box 5)
  - CD: Cornell University Big Red Marching Band, 2002; CD-1663 (Box 5)
  - CD: Fall Big Red Marching Band (2 copies), Fall 2003; CD-1664, 1665 (Box 5)
  - CD: Fall Big Red Marching Band, Fall 2004; CD-1666, 1667 (Box 5)
  - CD: Big Red Marching Band, 2007; CD-1668 (Box 5)
  - CD: Big Red Marching Band, 2008; CD-1669 (Box 5)
  - CD: Fall Big Red Marching Band, Fall 2004; CD-1666, 1667 (Box 5)
  - Film can and leader is labeled Cornell Band Roll. 1 Niagara, Princeton, Columbia, reel itself is labeled 1937 Syracuse, Colgate, Columbia, but may be a reused reel., 1949; F-370 (Box 12)
  - Label on can says early before 1953? band day. Reel itself says "This is Cornell" R-1. Footage is in color., Before 1953?; F-371 (Box 12)
  - Navy at Ithaca, October 4, 1952; F-372 (Box 12)
    Use DVD-764. includes footage of Bill the Goat the live Navy mascot and also Touchdown the Cornell bear costumed human in addition to the band formations. May include footage from other games as well.
  - Presidential Review, May 20, 1954; F-373 (Box 12)
  - Navy at Ithaca, October 6, 1956; F-385 (Box 12)
  - Penn at Philadelphia, November 22, 1956; F-374 (Box 12)
  - Unknown game at Cornell, date based on formation spelling out 1956. Footage shows the opposing team's band performance as well as Cornell's. Color., 1956?; F-375 (Box 12)
    Use DVD-764
  - Columbia at Columbia, November 1, 1958; F-376 (Box 12)
  - Princeton at Cornell, includes card listing formations, also labeled as Fall Weekend 1958-59, Lionel Hampton, Dad's Day, October 25, 1958; F-377 (Box 12)
  - Penn, includes car noting formations, ca. 1958-1959?; F-378 (Box 12)
  - Unlabeled 7" reel, F-379 (Box 12)
  - Unlabeled 7" reel, F-380 (Box 12)
  - Unlabeled 7" reel, F-381 (Box 12)
  - Unlabeled 10.5" reel, F-382 (Box 7)
  - BETA: Cornell Band, November 7, 1990; V-5975 (Box 6)
  - VHS: Cornell University Marching Band, Halftime of Pittsburgh Steelers at Buffalo Bills game (3 copies), September 30, 2001; V-5976-5978 (Box 6)